# **AKASH NAIR**

Frankfurt am Main, Hesse +49 0176-323-76787 akashon1@gmail.com www.skywide.in



## PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a DevOps engineer with nearly 3 years of experience on AWS, DevOps practices and scripting. I am seeking opportunities where I can use my skills to design and implement solutions that can improve and increase the velocity of software development

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## BlazeClan Technologies, India | Cloud Engineer

**DECEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2016** 

|   | Design of Highly Scalable and Fault Tolerant Architectures on the cloud |  |
|---|---|--|
|   | Migration of on-premise infrastructure to AWS                           |  |
|   | Configuration and troubleshooting of servers & networks                 |  |
|   | Implementation of server and network security measures                  |  |
|   | Optimisation of infrastructure and operations                           |  |
|   | Conducting routine security audits of systems and networks              |  |
| Key Skills: AWS, Vagrant, Python, Linux/Unix, Cloud Migration, Disaster Recovery, Solution Architecture |   |  |
| PTC Software, India   Software Analyst  |   |  |
| JULY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017  |   |  |
|   | Implementation of CI/CD pipelines for development teams using Jenkins   |  |
|   | Automation of processes and tasks using Python, Shell scripting         |  |
|   | Provisioning of infrastructure whenever required                        |  |
|   | Configuration management using Ansible                                  |  |
|   | Ensuring smooth deployments to production and test systems              |  |
| Key Skills: Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Shell Scripting, SCRUM, VPN, Papertrail                           |   |  |

## **EDUCATION**

University of Pune, India | Bachelors in Computer Science

AUGUST 2009 - APRIL 2012

**University of Pune, India** | Master of Computer Applications

AUGUST 2012 - APRIL 2015

## Frankfurt UAS, Germany I Masters in High Integrity Systems

OCTOBER 2017 - PRESENT

| CERTIF   | CATIONS   |
|----------|---|
| Pytho    | on Data Structures - University of Michigan on Coursera   |
|          | Certificate earned at Monday, March 7, 2016   |
| Using    | Python to Access Web Data - University of Michigan on Coursera  |
|          | Certificate earned at Monday, June 13, 2016   |
| AWS      | Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate  |
| 0        | Successfully completed the AWS Certification requirements and gained recognition as a AWS Certified Solutions Architect Certificate AWS-ASOA-6871 |
| SKILLS   | & INTERESTS   |
| Skills:  |   |
| 0 0 0 0  | Proficient in English writing and speaking.  Basic knowledge of German  Arduino programming  Java  Terraform  ELB                                 |
| Interest | es:   |
|          |   |

□ Solo travelling, playing guitar, hiking, meeting new people, reading history books